{
    "id": "1:0x03506eD3f57892C85DB20C36846e9c808aFe9ef4:111",
    "protocol": 1,
    "pointer": "bafkreiehyjmxswthfspayfjuaj2mkfig2gcv72wbbkt6gdjplgiert4df4",
    "data": {
        "title": "Otterscan",
        "description": "Otterscan is an open-source, fast, local, laptop-friendly Ethereum block explorer",
        "website": "https://otterscan.io",
        "projectTwitter": "otterscan",
        "userGithub": "otterscan",
        "projectGithub": "otterscan",
        "logoImg": "bafybeigoyezwswvwbedbf4b2gsr66tl5vfq5qdfiq3huwsivp37qmwd5ce",
        "bannerImg": "bafybeidh22fvqahrapg4j5nuzkmsox3nrcghgqdkjn6zdvvaswaglh3b34",
        "logoImgData": {},
        "bannerImgData": {},
        "credentials": {
            "twitter": {
                "@context": [
                    "https://www.w3.org/2018/credentials/v1"
                ],
                "type": [
                    "VerifiableCredential"
                ],
                "credentialSubject": {
                    "id": "did:pkh:eip155:1:0x35D1A101E55DA0C641e9379f2e4dfA3e2AE7F37b",
                    "@context": [
                        {
                            "hash": "https://schema.org/Text",
                            "provider": "https://schema.org/Text"
                        }
                    ],
                    "provider": "ClearTextTwitter#otterscan",
                    "hash": "v0.0.0:7ycSPQa1Uxj5m3/qUqvXCPcBN4xzsVjo9lKdkstqYbg="
                },
                "issuer": "did:key:z6MkghvGHLobLEdj1bgRLhS4LPGJAvbMA1tn2zcRyqmYU5LC",
                "issuanceDate": "2023-08-11T18:05:52.190Z",
                "proof": {
                    "type": "Ed25519Signature2018",
                    "proofPurpose": "assertionMethod",
                    "verificationMethod": "did:key:z6MkghvGHLobLEdj1bgRLhS4LPGJAvbMA1tn2zcRyqmYU5LC#z6MkghvGHLobLEdj1bgRLhS4LPGJAvbMA1tn2zcRyqmYU5LC",
                    "created": "2023-08-11T18:05:52.191Z",
                    "jws": "eyJhbGciOiJFZERTQSIsImNyaXQiOlsiYjY0Il0sImI2NCI6ZmFsc2V9..EnG9qAquZVIL_kO_bEh9Ua9d0NYWNTExzv0UY2ePHGKTKFB0C1AJ9OodML21AKUusD199--NvwWWo4_vOdV2AQ"
                },
                "expirationDate": "2023-11-09T18:05:52.190Z"
            },
            "github": {
                "@context": [
                    "https://www.w3.org/2018/credentials/v1"
                ],
                "type": [
                    "VerifiableCredential"
                ],
                "credentialSubject": {
                    "id": "did:pkh:eip155:1:0x35D1A101E55DA0C641e9379f2e4dfA3e2AE7F37b",
                    "provider": "ClearTextGithubOrg#otterscan#28685",
                    "hash": "v0.0.0:gMOvXqXInkFwoXeGPtrCrRO7kRkwmnH3hbzYtLxV5UE=",
                    "@context": [
                        {
                            "hash": "https://schema.org/Text",
                            "provider": "https://schema.org/Text"
                        }
                    ]
                },
                "issuer": "did:key:z6MkghvGHLobLEdj1bgRLhS4LPGJAvbMA1tn2zcRyqmYU5LC",
                "issuanceDate": "2023-08-11T18:06:16.214Z",
                "proof": {
                    "type": "Ed25519Signature2018",
                    "proofPurpose": "assertionMethod",
                    "verificationMethod": "did:key:z6MkghvGHLobLEdj1bgRLhS4LPGJAvbMA1tn2zcRyqmYU5LC#z6MkghvGHLobLEdj1bgRLhS4LPGJAvbMA1tn2zcRyqmYU5LC",
                    "created": "2023-08-11T18:06:16.214Z",
                    "jws": "eyJhbGciOiJFZERTQSIsImNyaXQiOlsiYjY0Il0sImI2NCI6ZmFsc2V9..PA38rbAmJIiIBD2zLvbSmxSznAtJno4AaCPWmbkUSgemE9d1TTt7h51PKzcS3-S_J-yzeyqXwDAfwQUcyPplCQ"
                },
                "expirationDate": "2023-11-09T18:06:16.214Z"
            }
        },
        "createdAt": 1673391009470
    },
    "applications": [
        {
            "id": "0xa1d52f9b5339792651861329a046dd912761e9a9-13",
            "protocol": 1,
            "pointer": "bafkreib3k5klox2c6nrexc5hrcf2sujkuybe2r33nkq7njr54iphkh6ene",
            "data": {
                "signature": "0x9e3c3ea940e7c3c6b9e297d63534e62eb6d97e12f818e6caed50f8f949ed72c42060b33f47876b9f137bfa3362ebe9129ebf2dca061127c976fc37eeb155732b1c",
                "application": {
                    "round": "0xa1d52f9b5339792651861329a046dd912761e9a9",
                    "recipient": "0xb7081Fd06E7039D198D10A8b72B824e60C1B1E16",
                    "project": {
                        "lastUpdated": 0,
                        "createdAt": 1673391009470,
                        "id": "1:0x03506eD3f57892C85DB20C36846e9c808aFe9ef4:111",
                        "title": "Otterscan",
                        "description": "Otterscan is an open-source, fast, local, laptop-friendly Ethereum block explorer",
                        "website": "https://otterscan.io",
                        "bannerImg": "bafybeidh22fvqahrapg4j5nuzkmsox3nrcghgqdkjn6zdvvaswaglh3b34",
                        "logoImg": "bafybeigoyezwswvwbedbf4b2gsr66tl5vfq5qdfiq3huwsivp37qmwd5ce",
                        "metaPtr": {
                            "protocol": "1",
                            "pointer": "bafkreiehyjmxswthfspayfjuaj2mkfig2gcv72wbbkt6gdjplgiert4df4"
                        },
                        "userGithub": "otterscan",
                        "projectGithub": "otterscan",
                        "projectTwitter": "otterscan",
                        "credentials": {
                            "twitter": {
                                "@context": [
                                    "https://www.w3.org/2018/credentials/v1"
                                ],
                                "type": [
                                    "VerifiableCredential"
                                ],
                                "credentialSubject": {
                                    "id": "did:pkh:eip155:1:0x35D1A101E55DA0C641e9379f2e4dfA3e2AE7F37b",
                                    "@context": [
                                        {
                                            "hash": "https://schema.org/Text",
                                            "provider": "https://schema.org/Text"
                                        }
                                    ],
                                    "provider": "ClearTextTwitter#otterscan",
                                    "hash": "v0.0.0:7ycSPQa1Uxj5m3/qUqvXCPcBN4xzsVjo9lKdkstqYbg="
                                },
                                "issuer": "did:key:z6MkghvGHLobLEdj1bgRLhS4LPGJAvbMA1tn2zcRyqmYU5LC",
                                "issuanceDate": "2023-08-11T18:05:52.190Z",
                                "proof": {
                                    "type": "Ed25519Signature2018",
                                    "proofPurpose": "assertionMethod",
                                    "verificationMethod": "did:key:z6MkghvGHLobLEdj1bgRLhS4LPGJAvbMA1tn2zcRyqmYU5LC#z6MkghvGHLobLEdj1bgRLhS4LPGJAvbMA1tn2zcRyqmYU5LC",
                                    "created": "2023-08-11T18:05:52.191Z",
                                    "jws": "eyJhbGciOiJFZERTQSIsImNyaXQiOlsiYjY0Il0sImI2NCI6ZmFsc2V9..EnG9qAquZVIL_kO_bEh9Ua9d0NYWNTExzv0UY2ePHGKTKFB0C1AJ9OodML21AKUusD199--NvwWWo4_vOdV2AQ"
                                },
                                "expirationDate": "2023-11-09T18:05:52.190Z"
                            },
                            "github": {
                                "@context": [
                                    "https://www.w3.org/2018/credentials/v1"
                                ],
                                "type": [
                                    "VerifiableCredential"
                                ],
                                "credentialSubject": {
                                    "id": "did:pkh:eip155:1:0x35D1A101E55DA0C641e9379f2e4dfA3e2AE7F37b",
                                    "provider": "ClearTextGithubOrg#otterscan#28685",
                                    "hash": "v0.0.0:gMOvXqXInkFwoXeGPtrCrRO7kRkwmnH3hbzYtLxV5UE=",
                                    "@context": [
                                        {
                                            "hash": "https://schema.org/Text",
                                            "provider": "https://schema.org/Text"
                                        }
                                    ]
                                },
                                "issuer": "did:key:z6MkghvGHLobLEdj1bgRLhS4LPGJAvbMA1tn2zcRyqmYU5LC",
                                "issuanceDate": "2023-08-11T18:06:16.214Z",
                                "proof": {
                                    "type": "Ed25519Signature2018",
                                    "proofPurpose": "assertionMethod",
                                    "verificationMethod": "did:key:z6MkghvGHLobLEdj1bgRLhS4LPGJAvbMA1tn2zcRyqmYU5LC#z6MkghvGHLobLEdj1bgRLhS4LPGJAvbMA1tn2zcRyqmYU5LC",
                                    "created": "2023-08-11T18:06:16.214Z",
                                    "jws": "eyJhbGciOiJFZERTQSIsImNyaXQiOlsiYjY0Il0sImI2NCI6ZmFsc2V9..PA38rbAmJIiIBD2zLvbSmxSznAtJno4AaCPWmbkUSgemE9d1TTt7h51PKzcS3-S_J-yzeyqXwDAfwQUcyPplCQ"
                                },
                                "expirationDate": "2023-11-09T18:06:16.214Z"
                            }
                        }
                    },
                    "answers": [
                        {
                            "questionId": 0,
                            "question": "Email Address",
                            "type": "email",
                            "hidden": true,
                            "encryptedAnswer": {
                                "ciphertext": "AbkAVLiw/Zg+7TlJIS/CxTXgDRgFmXlTODOIhz/foQ1qafaDB2+cDw4z4mWkeQ+3",
                                "encryptedSymmetricKey": "0dc7d21ea56560cde17e1b1d8be2f9fde2d543157060e31f2b64c7e18a07fe2cfdfb2b417e36fe9ebdc5ae3740de9e133e92a9f50fe45acf8530e236ff6dd18138d4ae61179ee9c52ca35ba8e8be7845404a1ff887c83de38d936deb51d4e8b41eec30dc4f27703daba7f878cd8aa02429f2a64c21e7ec75af490069ea5046a800000000000000205a8e01526763a58c1f3f80309db8adea042a77c910b6557c6bcc2b172f246e8f62a0a7e8f217aa8ea5c8ab6e61a1e38e"
                            }
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 1,
                            "question": "Project GitHub Repo (Not Team Page)",
                            "type": "link",
                            "hidden": false,
                            "answer": "https://github.com/otterscan/otterscan/"
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 2,
                            "question": "Telegram Handle (you can answer N/A)",
                            "type": "short-answer",
                            "hidden": true,
                            "encryptedAnswer": {
                                "ciphertext": "EX3lKiPXopMSl6oqsiWOj66LZjGF7PDNOM9tKTFqf84=",
                                "encryptedSymmetricKey": "e3a708330f732e559a0c125978aa8b575edff53852c59f213945632192b1dc8af8ab145a941658809cf695616213c10c11f00154cef2be3dc2decdc8fb7da4c1d6cb278b6d8008d6b5648d4725a3f276956945ad897c7f29796161dc3c4aa6ae76b70a8f9cf52f039a10dc808e5d224bfce9ac5dc1f6f6d2e21f33c09cd90b0b000000000000002003df04b7865d42f4fe6bddb5b62228fb75a32856ff32918f57a0851b2bc094bb31e7558a2226f0e6a5b895241e9e59b1"
                            }
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 3,
                            "question": "Gitcoin Gov Forum Handle (gov.gitcoin.co)",
                            "type": "short-answer",
                            "hidden": false
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 4,
                            "question": "Link to your Public Group Chat (Discord or Telegram )",
                            "type": "link",
                            "hidden": false
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 5,
                            "question": "How is your project in support of or directly advancing the Ethereum Network\u2019s infrastructure? ",
                            "type": "paragraph",
                            "hidden": false,
                            "answer": "Otterscan is the most affordable way for regular people to run a mainnet block explorer locally. Since everything is local, everything is fast, private, and it runs on consumer grade hardware.\n\nIt is built on top of Erigon, currently the only ETH client able to run an archive node on consumer grade hardware (syncs in < 1 week, takes ~2 TB; regular external SSDs do the work).\n\nOtterscan implements some non-standard JSON-RPC methods to extract additional information (e.g. internal ETH transfers) directly from Erigon DB.\n\nThen, we use this data with other public datasets (4bytes, Sourcify) to provide a 100% local block explorer. It is a SPA and requires only an Erigon archive node, no additional middleware (SQL DBs, indexers) is necessary.\n\nIt supports open standards like ENS, and widespread sources of info like Chainlink for getting historical price info directly from the archive, no external sources are needed.\n\nCommunity members have even made it available into a dappnode package."
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 6,
                            "question": "If you've participated in past grant rounds, please share any new updates or milestones from the prior months (N/A if you haven\u2019t participated previously). ",
                            "type": "paragraph",
                            "hidden": false,
                            "answer": "We've released multiple versions, please check our release notes:\n\n- https://github.com/otterscan/otterscan/releases/tag/v2.0.0\n- https://github.com/otterscan/otterscan/releases/tag/v2.1.0\n- https://github.com/otterscan/otterscan/releases/tag/v2.2.0"
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 7,
                            "question": "How do you measure the impact of your project? Please provide examples and/or standard metrics. This might be used in future impact reports ",
                            "type": "paragraph",
                            "hidden": false,
                            "answer": "# Problems we are trying to solve\n\n## Privacy\n\nNo info about your addresses is leaked to third-parties.\n\n## Availability\n\nIt runs against your node, as long as it has internet connectivity, the service is never down.\n\n## Consumer hardware friendly\n\nMost opensource solutions out there have large hardware requirements, making it unaffordable to run it at home.\n\n## Expand the API ecosystem\n\nSomething simple as getting the transactions from your addresses often requires using a third-party, centralized, closed source indexer.\n\nWe solved that problem for Otterscan by exposing that info directly from the node, and everyone can benefit from it."
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 8,
                            "question": "Total Prior Funding for the project in USD",
                            "type": "number",
                            "hidden": false,
                            "answer": "300000"
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 9,
                            "question": "Which of the following funding sources do you have? Check all that apply",
                            "type": "checkbox",
                            "hidden": false,
                            "answer": [
                                "Grants"
                            ]
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 10,
                            "question": "Total Team Size",
                            "type": "number",
                            "hidden": false,
                            "answer": "2"
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 11,
                            "question": "How old (in Months) is the project? (We will use Twitter, domain registration, github, etc)",
                            "type": "number",
                            "hidden": false,
                            "answer": "27"
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 12,
                            "question": "If you participated in past grant rounds using a different project payout wallet address, please share it here:",
                            "type": "address",
                            "hidden": true
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 13,
                            "question": "Profiles or socials of other main team members publicly associated with the project (N/A for solo founders): ",
                            "type": "paragraph",
                            "hidden": true,
                            "answer": "Twitter: https://twitter.com/wmitsuda"
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 14,
                            "question": "Have you read and confirmed your grant abides by the Program General Eligibility Policy? https://gitcoin.notion.site/GG18-Eligibility-cb4a5754c56043d4b3ed34eddbac261c?pvs=4",
                            "type": "short-answer",
                            "hidden": true,
                            "answer": "yes"
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 15,
                            "question": "Anything else you'd like to share about your project, previous work, or other project affiliations? Anything you'd like to add that may help in determining project eligibility?",
                            "type": "paragraph",
                            "hidden": false
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 16,
                            "question": "Would you like to opt-in to future messages from Gitcoin for updates, information, and/or interviews? ",
                            "type": "multiple-choice",
                            "hidden": true,
                            "answer": "Yes"
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 17,
                            "question": "Would you like to opt-in to us sharing your information with select third-parties for investment opportunities? ",
                            "type": "multiple-choice",
                            "hidden": true,
                            "answer": "Yes"
                        },
                        {
                            "questionId": 18,
                            "question": "Location/Region where the project is (primarily) based ",
                            "type": "multiple-choice",
                            "hidden": false,
                            "answer": "Central and South America"
                        }
                    ]
                }
            }
        }
    ]
}